Daniel Christianson

daniel.s.christianson@gmail.com

IT Support Technician • (6

(612) 702-0265

Minneapolis, MN

SUMMARY

IT Support Technician with 10 years' experience. Specialization in Windows deployment and scripting. Interested in working towards a career in programming and development. Mostly self-taught and on the job training. Education in graphic design and media arts. Excellent documentation creator. See my GitHub and personal website for more details on experience.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Software: WebStorm, Visual Studio, Atom, Notepad++, Sketch, Azure Active Directory, Microsoft Admin Center, O365, Intune, WDS / MDT, Citrix, GPO, Acronis, Configuration Manager (SCCM), Adobe Creative Cloud, Full Slate

Operating Systems: Windows 10/11, Windows Server, Mac OS, iOS, Android, some Linux Unbuntu

Databases: MySQL, Microsoft Access, Fox Pro

Programming/Scripting: PowerShell, VBA, JavaScript, JSON, Python, React, Angular, Node JS, Express JS, Phaser, Fox Pro, GIT GitHub: https://github.com/daniel-christianson/ LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-s-christianson/

Personal website: https://danielchristianson.page/

EDUCATION

Code School: 13 Online Courses (before they merged with Pluralsight https://www.pluralsight.com/codeschool)

Pluralsight: 12 Online Courses (https://www.pluralsight.com/)

Course Topics: JavaScript, C#, Python, React, Angular, Node JS, Express JS, GIT, Web Design,

UX Design PowerShell, Active Directory, Azure AD, Azure Intune

Normandale Community College: Associate of Fine Arts Degree Minneapolis College of Art and Design: Animation major Art Institute International MN: Media Arts & Animation major

WORK HISTORY

Hennepin County

December 2020 - Current (3 years)

IT Support

WFH / 7009 York Avenue South, Edina, MN 55435
Responsibilities

- Service Desk Software: Assyst.
- Environment: WFH help desk, onsite laptop exchange rotation.
- **Laptop Support:** Azure Intune troubleshooting: sync, wipe, escalate, etc.
- **Cisco IP Communicator Softphone Support:** setup, troubleshoot, repair.
- Active Directory: troubleshoot access issues, reset passwords.
- Always on VPN/MFA: troubleshoot connection issues, renew certificates, reset MFA.
- Configuration Manager (MS Endpoint CM): remote control, reinstall client, remote manage.
- Software Center: assist with app installs and updates, troubleshoot issues, clear cache, reinstall client, etc.
- iPhone Support: Azure Intune, remote assistance with updates, Company Portal connection, Outlook contacts, etc.

Accenture SUS / Amadeus-Navitaire

July 2017 – October 2020 (3 years)

Corporate Office – 333 South 7th Street, Suite 1700, Minneapolis, MN 55402

IT Support

Responsibilities

- **Service Desk Software:** Remedy, Service Now.
- Environment: in-office helpdesk, 2-person team in Minneapolis, after hours on-call rotation.
- Laptop/Asset Support: imaging SME, procurement, deployment, inventory, troubleshoot, repair, decommission.
- **VoIP Phone Support:** setup, troubleshoot, repair, decommission.
- Active Directory: new hires, roll-offs, add/remove AD groups, add/remove computers, reset passwords.
- Configuration Manager (SCCM): compliance reports, compliance emails, security updates.
- RSA/VPN/MFA/Symantec Support: assign tokens, troubleshoot connection issues, reset PINs.
- Office Network Printer Support: 3 local printers/fax/scanners, 1 local multimedia printer.
- Audio/Video Conference Room Support: 10 local conference rooms.

Notable Scripting and Automation at Accenture

SCCM Laptop Compliance Auto-email Script

Technology Used: PowerShell, VBA Excel

Summary: Created a script that ran weekly, analyzed the output of a laptop compliance report from SCCM, kept track of how many emails each user was sent, and automatically sent different types of emails to users depending on their compliance status.

Details:

- The first part of the script was written in VBA to iterate through the Excel compliance spreadsheet created by SCCM and add non-compliant users to a CSV file.
- The second part of the script was written in PowerShell to evoke the Outlook COM object.
 Using data from the CSV file, it sent different emails to the user depending on the issue and how many times they had been notified.

Active Directory Automation

Technology Used: PowerShell

Summary: Worked on various tools/scripts to automate common AD tasks.

Examples:

- "Mass Remove AD Group Membership" PowerShell script to remove inactive users from specified AD group and document changes in a log file.
- "Temp Password Generator" PowerShell script to generate a temp password without similar-looking characters. Ex: O, O, I, I, etc.
- "New AD User Tool" A customized AD user creation tool with a GUI.
- "Delete AD Computer Tool" Offboarding tool used to delete a specified AD computer and create a log file with BitLocker recovery info and local admin password. Log file would then be saved to a secure location in case data on the computer needed to be accessed again.

Laptop Imaging Automation

Technology Used: PowerShell, VB

Summary: Customized Microsoft Deployment Toolkit (MDT) to automate laptop imaging.

Customizations:

- "Remote Imaging via USB drive" During COVID, I studied and modified several of MDT's VB scripts in order to image laptops remotely via USB stick. I had it suppress the automated "domain join" function so it could continue to the point where VPN software was installed, then it would pause and produce a pop-up window "click to continue". The support agent would connect to VPN, continue, then the "domain join" would run.
- "Active Directory Computer Account Scripts"
 - > Script to move the AD computer account to the correct OU based on its default gateway at the time of imaging (different OUs per office location).
 - > Script to retrieve user's email from AD and assign it to the computer's AD description.
 - > Script to grab laptop's serial number from BIOS and save it to AD as a custom attribute.
- "Custom Start Menu with OneDrive and Teams" We already had a customized start menu and taskbar, but I researched a way to add OneDrive and Teams icons. It was challenging at the time because the apps only installed once the user logged on for the first time.
- "WDS Backup / Replication Tool" Helped update and add features to an extensive robocopy script with menu options for backing up MDT files and replicating changes to all office locations (MSP, SLC, MNL, LON, and SYD). After ran on a given server, it would restart the WDS service to ensure the changes were live.

Lifetouch National School Studios

March 2013 – July 2017 (4 years)

Production Lab - 7800 Picture Drive Bloomington, MN

IT Support

Responsibilities

- Service Desk Software: Hewlett Packard Service Desk (HPSD), Service Now.
- **Environment:** onsite 10-person team that handled IT and network needs of entire factory.
- After Hours Support: on-call rotation, calls were common and often required travel to the site.
- **Desktop/Laptop/Asset Support:** procurement, deployment, inventory, troubleshooting, repair, decommission.
- **Application Support:** upwards of 50 in-house applications, each with unique install/troubleshooting instructions.
- Database Corrections: old Fox Pro DBFs and MySQL, regularly queried and corrected data to fix application issues.
 Network Support: two server/network rooms, troubleshot network connections, ran LAN lines to patch panels.
- Server Monitoring: Windows Servers 2008/2012, troubleshoot apache tomcats, IIS restarts, search log files.

...Responsibilities at Lifetouch continued

- Active Directory: troubleshot AD groups/permissions but escalated when changes were needed.
- Windows XP to Windows 7 migrations (and exchange server to O365): facilitated end user migrations.
- Office Network Printer Support: around 100 local office printers of varying brands and models.
- Industrial Multimedia Printer Support: around 30 local printers (HP and Noritsu).
- Rimage Support (CD/DVD printing hardware): rimage SME, setup, backup, troubleshooting, repair.
- Audio/Video Conference Room Support: 2-3 conference rooms.

Notable Scripting and Automation at Lifetouch

Fox Pro Report-Generating Program

Technology Used: Fox Pro, VBA for Excel

Summary: I rewrote and expanded on an old set of scripts and created a program with a GUI for end users to run and create various reports on their own.

Details:

- The scripts were originally run by IT to generate several reports for supervisors with factory statistics. First the data was pulled from multiple CSV files and DBF tables, then it was imported into Excel for consolidation and formatting over several pages and spreadsheets, and finally the spreadsheets were saved to a network share for production supervisors to review.
- To generate all the necessary reports an IT support agent spent around 2 hours manually running the scripts over and over, changing certain parameters each time for different reports.
- I consolidated several of the scripts into different modules and used functions, passing parameters to generate and save all the reports automatically.
- Then I created a GUI version with various options to generate custom reports as needed.
- Part of the challenge was finding an easy way to update some of the backend data due to the fact that it changed each year as production labs took on new work and processes were assigned to different locations. I accomplished this by including an option in the GUI that opened up the relevant DBF table so it could be modified. After saving the modified table, the program automatically updated the Excel templates accordingly.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

GitHub

Please check out my GitHub repo page for examples of projects I've worked on.

URL: https://github.com/daniel-christianson?tab=repositories

Personal Website

Technologies Used: WebStorm, JavaScript, React, GitHub

URL: https://danielchristianson.page/

Hosted on GitHub here: https://github.com/daniel-christianson/my-portfolio-website

Note: Website is a work-in-progress. Not much to see currently. Mostly just a project to learn about working with React and modules in JavaScript, and webhosting through GitHub. I used react-router for page/path generating, and I used react-code-blocks to display code snippets with typical styling.

Game Development

Technology Used: Phaser (Phaser JS, Matter JS, JavaScript), Godot (GDScript, C#), Unity (C#), Photoshop, Tiled **Summary:** Been playing around with a couple different game engines to learn a bit about game development. **Details:**

- Started with Phaser tutorials, then created a few of my own concept tests with help from API documentation.
- Made a 2D side-scrolling test with platforms and simple enemy objects.
- Made a 2D top-down test with buildings you could enter/exit, causing roof tiles to disappear/reappear.
- Took a couple Pluralsight courses on Unity along with several C# courses.
- Found it a fun way to learn more about programming.